<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Spine Nuances</title>
    <link>https://spinenuances.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Spine Nuances</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright @ 2021 Spine Nuances. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://spinenuances.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Composite Materials - Game Changers</title>
      <link>https://spinenuances.com/blog/game_changer_composite/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spinenuances.com/blog/game_changer_composite/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-composite-materials&#34;&gt;What are composite materials?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Composite materials are in essence a combination of at least two materials with different chemical properties that only mix on a macroscopic level.
The individual components remain physically distinct, the resulting composite structure behaves as one.
In this manner composite materials are designed to leverage the ‘best’ parts of the individual constituents and combine them into a &lt;a href=&#34;https://saps2412.github.io/sales_mktg/what_is_ostaPek_and_why.pdf&#34;&gt;new composite material&lt;/a&gt; with superior properties.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spinal Anatomy, Modern Concepts</title>
      <link>https://spinenuances.com/blog/spinal_anatomy_modern_concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spinenuances.com/blog/spinal_anatomy_modern_concepts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All things spinal. Anatomy as a living language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hidden behind a somewhat generic title, “&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.springer.com/gp/book/9783030209247&#34;&gt;Spinal Anatomy, Modern Concepts&lt;/a&gt;,” we discover pearls for anyone
interested in the spine. It is edited by &lt;a href=&#34;https://courses.eccelearning.com/faculty/dr-jean-marc-vital&#34;&gt;Prof. Jean Marc Vital&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Derek-Cawley&#34;&gt;Dr. Derek Thomas Cawley&lt;/a&gt;, both from the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chu-bordeaux.fr&#34;&gt;University of Bordeaux&lt;/a&gt;, with its long established tradition that combines the study of spine surgery,
anatomy and physiology. In Bordeaux, these subjects seem inseparable and must be continuously renewed.
Vibrantly written, magnificently illustrated, to plunge inside is to find what chapter authors, &lt;a href=&#34;https://courses.eccelearning.com/faculty/prof-alain-dimeglio&#34;&gt;Dimeglio&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.taylorfrancis.com/chapters/edit/10.1201/9780429352416-7/normal-abnormal-development-growth-spine-thoracic-cage-federico-canavese-fran%C3%A7ois-bonnel-alain-dimeglio&#34;&gt;Bonnel&lt;/a&gt;
call, anatomy as a “living language” and to explore its “inexhaustible fecundity.” That is, the spine’s
incessant capacity to adapt and transform. The authors remind us that anatomy, as a story, has been told
“since the origin of humans.” And yet still, from each generation’s technology and prospective, it must be
told again and again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next generation flexStaas pedicle screw system receives 510(k) clearance</title>
      <link>https://spinenuances.com/blog/gii_flexstaas_pedicle_screw_fda_clearance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spinenuances.com/blog/gii_flexstaas_pedicle_screw_fda_clearance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://spinenuances.com/&#34;&gt;Spine Nuances&lt;/a&gt; is excited to announce that the &lt;a href=&#34;https://spinenuances.com/products/GII_pedicle_fixation&#34;&gt;GII pedicle fixation&lt;/a&gt; system now includes
the next generation flexStaas pedicle screw that was recently cleared by the FDA for the US market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flexStaas pedicle screw as part of the Coligne GII spinal fixation system is intended to provide immobilization and stabilization of spinal segments in skeletally mature patients as an adjunct to fusion.
The poly-axial flexStaas pedicle screw features (1) a tulip design with a large docking surface and click grip for a fast and strong connection,
(2) double helix cancellous thread with a self-tapping tip for fast and precise screw placement and (3) an increased resistance to torque.
The set screw has (1) a wide self-aligning thread that facilitates set screw positioning and tightening and
(2) a torx interface to increase axial compression for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.coligne.com/international/home.html&#34;&gt;Coligne&lt;/a&gt; Titanium rods.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ostaPek® carbon composite - Biomechanics</title>
      <link>https://spinenuances.com/blog/ostapek_carbon_composite_part_two_biomechanics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spinenuances.com/blog/ostapek_carbon_composite_part_two_biomechanics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ostaPek® is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.coligne.com/international/home.html&#34;&gt;Coligne&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; proprietary &lt;a href=&#34;https://saps2412.github.io/sales_mktg/what_is_ostaPek_and_why.pdf&#34;&gt;carbon composite material&lt;/a&gt; for spine fusion indications.
It comprises 67% long, continuous carbon fibers embedded in a 33% PEKEKK matrix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In comparison to state-of-the-art materials for spinal fusion, such as metals or PEEK, ostaPek® carbon composite has potential advantages in
at least three areas playing a major role in spine fusion: &lt;a href=&#34;https://spinenuances.com/blog/ostapek_carbon_composite_part_one_biology&#34;&gt;biology&lt;/a&gt;, biomechanics, and response to radiation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ever wonder what fusion with ostaPek® implants looks like?</title>
      <link>https://spinenuances.com/blog/ostapek_acif_fusion_c6-c7_canine_spinal_column/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spinenuances.com/blog/ostapek_acif_fusion_c6-c7_canine_spinal_column/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jacky, a male Rottweiler age 11, suffered from tetraplegia that also restricted his mobility at the cervical spine and was associated with pain.
MRI found a disc-protrusion with dynamic compression of the spinal cord at the C6-7 level.
He was diagnosed with chronic progressive Caudal Cervical Spondylomyelopathy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burst Fracture C7 - Trabis™ Cervical Corpectomy</title>
      <link>https://spinenuances.com/blog/c7_burst_fracture_trabis_cervical_corpectomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spinenuances.com/blog/c7_burst_fracture_trabis_cervical_corpectomy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pre-op images illustrate the case of a polytraumatized 19-year-old woman involved in a motor vehicle accident, diagnosed with a one-level (C7) burst fracture. The backward movement of the posterior wall of C7 lead to a decrease in muscular tonus in the upper limbs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ostaPek® carbon composite - Biology</title>
      <link>https://spinenuances.com/blog/ostapek_carbon_composite_part_one_biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spinenuances.com/blog/ostapek_carbon_composite_part_one_biology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ostaPek® is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://saps2412.github.io/sales_mktg/what_is_ostaPek_and_why.pdf&#34;&gt;carbon composite material&lt;/a&gt; developed and made by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.coligne.com/international/home.html&#34;&gt;Coligne&lt;/a&gt;
for spine fusion applications, since 1994. It is made of 67% long oriented carbon fibers embedded in a 33% PEKEKK matrix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When thinking of potential advantages of ostaPek® carbon composite compared to state-of-the-art materials for spinal fusion, such as PEEK or metals,
there are at least 3 major fields where ostaPek® can have an impact: biology, biomechanics, and response to radiation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instruments in the Surgeon&#39;s Hands</title>
      <link>https://spinenuances.com/blog/instrument_in_surgeons_hands/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spinenuances.com/blog/instrument_in_surgeons_hands/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spine fusion surgery is a hands-on craft and art. From a design point of view, the observation of the surgeons’ gestures
is most helpful as we see how objects are held and what they represent to the surgeon, the nurse, and the operative staff.
They point, hold, review.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trabis™ &amp; ACIF ostaPek® carbon composite cages in the US market</title>
      <link>https://spinenuances.com/blog/trabis_acif_regular_clinical_use_usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spinenuances.com/blog/trabis_acif_regular_clinical_use_usa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spine Nuances is excited to announce that both the &lt;a href=&#34;https://spinenuances.com/products/trabis_cervical_corpectomy_vertebral_body_replacement_cage&#34;&gt;Trabis™&lt;/a&gt; cervical corpectomy and &lt;a href=&#34;https://spinenuances.com/products/acif_anterior_cervical_interbody_fusion_cage&#34;&gt;ACIF&lt;/a&gt; (Anterior Cervical Interbody Fusion) cage systems are being used regularly in various spinal centers across the USA. Both the Trabis™ and ACIF cages are made from ostaPek®, Coligne’s proprietary carbon composite material. OstaPek®, made of long carbon fibers embedded in a reinforced polymer matrix, has a European clinical history of over 25 years. Both spinal cage systems are designed to provide a superior solution to spinal surgeons working to optimize bone fusion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Primary malignant spine tumors</title>
      <link>https://spinenuances.com/blog/primary_malignant_tumors_spine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spinenuances.com/blog/primary_malignant_tumors_spine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Very informative and interesting new clinical publication that summarizes therapy planning, treatment concept and surgical techniques for primary malignant tumors of the spine
as part of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thieme-connect.com/products/ejournals/journal/10.1055/s-00000132&#34;&gt;Thieme E-Journals - Orthopädie und Unfallchirurgie up2date&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GEER webinar on Vertebral Tumors</title>
      <link>https://spinenuances.com/blog/geer_webinar_vertebral_tumors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spinenuances.com/blog/geer_webinar_vertebral_tumors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of their 34th National Congress, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3175830/&#34;&gt;GEER&lt;/a&gt; the Multidisciplinary Spanish Society for Spine Specialists is organizing a free webinar on Vertebral Tumors: Considerations in Resection and Reconstruction on Thursday, 10 December 2020, from 13:30 to 15:00 (CET).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spine Nuances open for business</title>
      <link>https://spinenuances.com/blog/spinenuances_open_for_business/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spinenuances.com/blog/spinenuances_open_for_business/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to announce that we are now open for business as Spine Nuances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the outstanding performance of &lt;a href=&#34;https://spinenuances.com/ostapek_carbon_composite&#34;&gt;ostaPek®&lt;/a&gt; carbon composite spine implants during the past 30 years in Europe,
Spine Nuances focus is to establish the ostaPek® technology as well as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.coligne.com/international/home.html&#34;&gt;Coligne&lt;/a&gt; products in the North American market as one of the leading brands for spine fusion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Composites for Medical Devices</title>
      <link>https://spinenuances.com/blog/swiss_medtech_webinar_composites_for_medical_devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spinenuances.com/blog/swiss_medtech_webinar_composites_for_medical_devices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.swiss-medtech.ch/en&#34;&gt;Swiss Medtech&lt;/a&gt; webinar on the advantages and challenges of composite in medical devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An expert panel answered questions on the advantages and challenges of composites based on their tailor-made material combination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A particular focus was given to the implementation of composites in medical devices under the current regulatory environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>