<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coligne Courses on Spine Nuances</title>
    <link>https://spinenuances.com/courses/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Coligne Courses on Spine Nuances</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright @ 2021 Spine Nuances. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://spinenuances.com/courses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Spine Surgeon Workshop</title>
      <link>https://spinenuances.com/courses/spine_surgeon_workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spinenuances.com/courses/spine_surgeon_workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hands-on sessions on spine cadavers or in an anatomy lab, to explore ostaPek® carbon composite spine surgery or nuances to surgical approaches.
Teachers and students flip role often during the same session. Participation and exchange.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer Sessions</title>
      <link>https://spinenuances.com/courses/developer_session/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spinenuances.com/courses/developer_session/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every surgeon, nurse, sales assistant and technical person knows how to improve a system.
But development is possible only via sustainable steps that really bring value. Discussions, sketches, case presentations are the starting point for change.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Surgeries</title>
      <link>https://spinenuances.com/courses/live_surgeries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spinenuances.com/courses/live_surgeries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a few dense days, hosts and guests join for a spectrum of ostaPek® surgical treatments. Guests become part of the case work up.
You&amp;rsquo;ll observe the hosts performing surgery and participate in the post-op briefings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Host &amp; guest tours</title>
      <link>https://spinenuances.com/courses/host_guest_tours/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spinenuances.com/courses/host_guest_tours/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some gestures, details, adjustments can only be learned by observing a colleague performing surgery, in a private and protected occasion.
Change of settings and a different perspective on a patient always bring ideas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NSpine Courses and Conferences</title>
      <link>https://spinenuances.com/courses/nspine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spinenuances.com/courses/nspine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;NSpine aspires to be the worlds most comprehensive spine review course;
a unique learning environment which seeks to amalgamate the latest research and surgical practice in the treatment of the spine.
Catering to all manner of professionals across the globe’s healthcare industry, from doctors and nurses through to anaesthetists and vets,
we gather the leading lights in spinal disciplines to advance your knowledge of best practice procedures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>